Guide to the Frank Schonfeld Papers WAG.027
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series XIV: By-Laws, 1960-1993
  Includes materials related campaigns to reform or amend District By-Laws, as well as various proposals to solidify autocracy or institute democratic reforms.
  - By-Laws, District Council, 1966-1993 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - DC 9 By-Laws: Proposals and Amendments; Ballots; Palm Cards, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - DC 9 Locals - By-Laws (L. 19; L. 230; L. 848; L. 905; L. 1011), undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - By-Laws: Joint Industry Board (Painting and Decorating Industry), undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence in re By-Laws, 1978-1980 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - DC 9 By-Laws: Letters of Advocacy (Pro and Con), 1960-1979 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Series XV: Referenda, 1960-1993
  Includes materials related to major fights within District Council 9, including a campaign to establish a Painters Section, Autonomous Locals, and attempts to reorganize the union.
  - Brooklyn, Queens Locals: Affiliation with DC 9, 1960-1962 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Autonomous Locals: Resolutions, Flyers, undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - DC 9: Quarterly Buttons Referendum, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Referenda Materials, 1965-1985 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - By-Laws Referendum (Mailgram), 1971 August 20 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Referendum: Painters Section, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Referendum: Painters Section (Text), 1970 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Resolutions; Amendments, 1965-1976 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Referendum on Re-organization, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Petition to Dismiss Charges against Schonfeld and to Unify Locals, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 16)
- Series XVI: Collective Bargaining Agreements, 1926-1978
  Includes agreements and proposed agreements, materials on negotiations (limited), and the controversial U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) Agreement.
  - DC 9 Agreements, 1926-1978 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - C.B. Proposals; Amendments; Negotiations, 1909-1992 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Trade Agreement, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Agreement; Negotiations, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Hardwood Finishers: Agreements, 1962-1964 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Ben Strauss Industries; Greenpoint Med. Center, 1973-1978 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Agreement for Re-Hab Standards, 1976-1977 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - HUD Memo of Understanding, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 24)
- Series XVII: Strikes and Work Stoppages, 1939-1977
  Includes materials on anti-member activities within the union. Examples include documents on the Paperhangers Local 490 strike, wherein the District Council asserted, "There is no strike," and encouraged the membership to cross Local 490's picket lines; and the Woodfinishers Strike opposing the corrupt bargaining efforts of leadership.
  - Bing and Bing - Strike Information; Bulletins ("Maintenance Men"), circa 1939 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - DC 9: Strikes (Flyers; Strike Bulletins, etc.), 1940-1941 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - DC 9: Strike (Report), 1967 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - DC 9: Strike (Agreement; Flyers; Correspondence), 1968 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - DC 9: Strike Bulletins, 1968 August 8-1968 September 8 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Press and Publicity: Strike, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - DC 9: Strike (Special Bulletin: Painters Free Press), 1977 August (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Local 490: Paperhangers Strike, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Hardwood Finishers Strikes, 1963-1970 (Box 13, Folder 33)
- Series XVIII: Proceedings, 1946-1992
  Includes conference and convention proceedings of the New York State Conference of Painters and the International Brotherhood of Painters.
  - NY State Conference of Painters, 1967-1975 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - NY State Conference of Painters; Correspondence, Proceedings, 1975-1976 (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - IBPAT: 17th Convention Proceedings, 1946 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - IBPAT: 18th Convention Proceedings, 1950 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - IBPAT: 20th Convention Proceedings, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - IBPAT: 21st Convention Proceedings, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - IBPAT: 22nd Convention Proceedings, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - IBPAT: 23rd Convention Proceedings, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - IBPAT: 23rd Convention: Officers Reports; Souvenir Book, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - IBPAT: 24th Convention: Proceedings and Resolutions, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Convention Materials: Resolutions; Correspondence, etc., 1969-1992 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Series XIX: Publications and Ephemera, 1909-1992
  Includes standard items issued by the union, both NYC and the International, as well as background material on issues documented in other series in this collection, such as the Maintenance Mechanics (see also the Inter-Local Caucus Election Materials) and various materials from the Schonfeld administration. A historically significant document in this series is the 1909 statement on an injunction.
  - IBPAT and Chicago DC 14: Directory: Business Agents, 1964-1967 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - DC 9: Pamphlets, 1909-1965 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Proposals on Educational Dept. (DC 9), 1947 October (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Organizing the Un-organized: Maintenance Mechanics, 1943 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Report of Organizing Activity (M. Rarback), 1948 January (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - IBPAT Promotional Flyers, undated (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - DC 9: Background Material, undated (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Schonfeld Administration: Program Proposals; DC 9 Information, undated (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Jubilee Banquet: Local 905, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Inter-Local Council of Progressive Painters: Annual Entertainment, 1948-1949 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Testimonial Dinner: Sidney Aaronson; L.U. 1011, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Testimonial Dinner: F. Schonfeld, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Testimonial Dinner: S. Frank Raftery, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Testimonial Dinner: Peter Brennan, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Testimonial Dinner: James Wolford, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Testimonial Materials, 1958-1979 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Strike Assessment: Official Report, 1934 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - DC 9: LM-2's, 1965-1992 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Employers Weekly Outstanding Receivables, 1978-1979 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - DC 9: Medical Plan; H.I.P. Materials, undated (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Life Insurance: DC 9 (Union Labor Life Insurance Co.), 1948, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Pensions and Politics: Eugene Calden (Retirees Club of DC 9), undated (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Reports: Painting Industry Insurance Fund, 1947-1958 (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Painting Industry Insurance Fund (Brochures), undated (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Bay Area Painters Pension and Welfare Fund (CA), 1964-1966 (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - DC 9 and IBPAT: Informational Brochures; Materials, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - DC 9: Lists of Employers (Master Painting Assoc.), 1947-1973 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Union Democracy Materials (Legal Cases; Awards; Ethical Practices Code), 1958-1974 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Tenant Rights (Brochures), undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Demonstration Guides (NYCLU), undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Working in NYC: Mayor's Committee on Exploitation of Workers (R. F. Wagner), undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Unemployment Insurance: NY State (Brochures), undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Social Security (Brochures), undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Disability; Rehabilitation; Home Relief (Brochures, etc.), undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Local 1011: Meeting Notices; Election Materials, etc., undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Palm Cards: Frank Schonfeld, undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Palm Cards: Rank-and-File, undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Palm Cards: Progressives, undated (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Palm Cards: United Active Team ("Active" Candidates), undated (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Palm Cards: James Bishop, undated (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Palm Cards: Individuals (Aaronson-Topp), undated (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Palm Cards: Locals (#25 - #1511), undated (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Palm Cards: Spanish, undated (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Palm Cards: Yiddish, undated (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Palm Cards: Various Clubs, undated (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Meeting Notices (Misc.), undated (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Labor Day Parade Notices, undated (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - By-Laws and Constitutions, DC 9 Locals (Bound), undated (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Pension Plan, Local Union #377: "Q and A" Brochure, undated (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - By-Laws, DC 9 (Bound), 1920-1944 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Trade Agreements, DC 9 (Bound), 1932-1971 (Box 15, Folder 26)
- Series XX: Photographs, 1940-1973
  Includes photographs of the 1968 DC 9 strike, general membership meetings and votes, and group and individual portraits of union officials.
  - Martin Rarback: Election Campaigns, circa 1946-1947 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Painters' Social Club, 1967 March (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Frank Schonfeld: Inauguration: District Council 9, 1967 September (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - DC 9 General Membership Meeting (Manhattan Center, NYC), 1967 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Frank Schonfeld and Various Union Officers, circa 1967-1968 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - DC 9 Members Vote to Strike, 1968 July (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - DC 9 Members Vote to Continue Strike, 1968 August (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - DC 9 Painters on Strike: Picketing, 1968 August-1968 September (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - United Federation of Teachers (UFT) Support the DC 9 Painters' Strike, 1968 August-1968 September (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - DC 9 Painters on Strike: Labor Day Parade, 1968 September 1 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - DC 9 Members Vote to Settle Strike, 1968 September 8 (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Frank Schonfeld: Portrait, circa 1968 (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Chartering Ceremony for New Civil Service Local, circa 1969 (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Installation Ceremony (Marc Ballroom, NYC), 1970 July (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Evidence: Business Agent Allowed Spray Painting on Roller Job, 1973 (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous (Coop City, Apprentices, Officials), undated (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Retired Painters: DC 9 Pensioners and Officials (Florida), undated (Box 43, Folder 17)
- Series XXI: 2014 Accretion: Unpublished Manuscript, late 1950s (Box 45)
  This series consists of materials created by Schonfeld in the course of writing his unpublished manuscript, including index cards, handwritten notes, a handwritten draft, and a typescript.
- Series XXII: Unprocessed Materials, 1927-1988
  - District Council 9: Financial Records, Minutes (1969-circa 1973) and Election Tallies; Legal Case against Schonfeld and The Story of Insurgency and Reform in the Painters Union, 1960-1967 (manuscript by Schonfeld and Dow Wilson), circa 1969-late 1970s (Box 16)
  - Legal Case against Schonfeld and District Council 9 Photographs, circa 1972 - circa 1978 (Box 17)
  - Schonfeld's Campaigns for Election and Re-election as Secretary-Treasurer and President (includes ephemera), Conference and Dinner Programs, Flyers, Local 1101 Financial Audits and Correspondence, District Council 9 Correspondence and Bylaws, Files on Corruption and the Murder of Dow Wilson, and Pension Fund Records, 1927-1986 (Box 18)
  - Schonfeld's Campaigns for Election and Re-election as Secretary-Treasurer and President (includes ephemera), District Council 9 Financial Records, Board of Trustees of the Painting Insurance, Annuity and Pension Funds Minutes (1979), Pension Fund Records, Labor Committee Against Corruption in the Painting Industry, Speaking Notes, and a Small Number of Photographs of Painting Sites, 1934-1988 (Box 19)